(upbeat music)
- [Instructor] In the next exercise, we want to allow
every components to access the global state.
So, for that we're going to use another hook,
which is use context.
It's another react hook that lets you read and subscribe
to the context changes from a functional components.
So, we're going to add this one.
We're going to call it from the functional components
and pass a context object as a parameter.
Then, it's going to return a global state as a value.
So, let's do the same inside our app components.
We're going to add this to the scope, use context,
and we need also to pass the context object as a parameter.
So, we're going to go back to here, the context,
and we want to make sure that we export this context,
so we can import it from outside.
So, we're going to import like this.
And so, inside here the app components,
I'm going to call use context and pass context as an object.
And I'm going to add a debugger statement
just to make a quick demo.
Let's just make sure that the app is up and running.
So, now, we open the inspector tool
and we check the reactive tools.
Here we go.
And I'm going to refresh because I'd like
the applications to stop right here.
So, now you can see that you have access
to a value with inside an array,
an array that includes the state
and also the dispatch function.
So, that's exactly what we need.
So, basically, what we're going to do, let's go back.
So, instead of using use register,
we no longer need to use use register
because we're not going to keep now the state management
at the top level of the root components.
Instead, we're going to allow every component
to subscribe to the context changes.
So, we're going to be able to do that separately.
Like this, it's going to work,
and if we try, actually it's going to work.
Yeah, we're going to be able to run the app again,
like this, let's try that.
Okay, so that should be 37.
Let's try to get that right, excellent.
Okay, so the thing is for now,
what we need to do is to allow other components
to also subscribe to the context changes.
In doing so, we can avoid passing data down
from parents to child by using the props.
So, the next exercise will be for you
to also allow every component like the form
and also the result components to subscribe
to the context changes and to eliminate
one-by-one all the props like this.
And we're going to see the solutions together
in the next video.